In the PCA algorithm we take
在PCA算法中，我们将（字幕整理：中国海洋大学，黄海广，haiguang2000@qq.com）
N dimensional features and reduce
N维特征减少
them to some K dimensional feature representation.
为某k维特征。
This number K is a parameter
这个数字K是PCA算法
of the PCA algorithm.
的一个参数。
This number K is also called
这个数K也被称为
the number of principle components
主成分的数字
or the number of principle components that we've retained.
或者，我们保留的主成分的数字。
And in this video I'd like
在这个视频中，我想
to give you some guidelines,
给你们一些指引，
tell you about how people
告诉你们一般情况下人们
tend to think about how to
如何考虑
choose this parameter K for PCA.
选取这个参数K。
In order to choose k,
为了选择K，
that is to choose the number
即选择这个主成分的
of principal components, here are a couple of useful concepts.
数字，这里有几个有用的概念。
What PCA tries to do
PCA试图
is it tries to minimize
去减少
the average squared projection error.
投影误差平方的平均值。
So it tries to minimize
因此，它试图减少
this quantity, which I'm writing down,
这个数量，就是我正在写的这个，
which is the difference between the
它是
original data X and the
原始数据X和
projected version, X-approx-i, which
投影，X约-i(上个视频中定义）
was defined last video, so
所以
it tries to minimize the squared
它试图尽量减少
distance between x and it's projection
x和x在低维面的投影
onto that lower dimensional surface.
距离的差的平方
So that's the average square projection error.
所以这是投影误差平方的平均值。
Also let me define the
同时我也将定义
total variation in the
数据的总方差
data to be the
为样本X的平方和
average length squared of
的平均值
these examples Xi
so the total variation in the
所以数据的
data is the average of
总方差就是
my training sets of the
我的训练集中
length of each of my training examples.
每个训练样本的平均长度
And this one says, "On average, how
这个说明了：“平均来说，
far are my training examples
我的训练样本
from the vector, from just being all zeros?"
距离全零向量的距离“
How far is, how far
或者说，我的训练样本
on average are my training examples from the origin?
距离原点有多远？
When we're trying to choose k, a
当我们试图选择K，
pretty common rule of thumb
一个常见的
for choosing k is to choose
经验方法是
the smaller values so that
选择较小的值，
the ratio between these is less than 0.01.
使得这两者之间的比值小于0.01。
So in other words,
换句话说，
a pretty common way to
一个很常见的方式，
think about how we choose k
来选择K
is we want the average squared projection error.
是我们想让平均投影误差平方
That is the average distance
即x和其投影的
between x and it's projections
平均距离
divided by the total variation of the data.
除以数据的总方差（
That is how much the data varies.
数据的波动程度）。
We want this ratio to be
我们希望这个比例
less than, let's say, 0.01.
比如说，小于0.01
Or to be less than 1%, which is another way of thinking about it.
或小于1％，这是另一种表述方式。
And the way most people think
而且大多数人
about choosing K is rather
选择K
than choosing K directly the
并不是像多数人谈论的那样
way most people talk about
直接进行选择
it is as what this
这是因为这个数
number is, whether it is 0.01
无论是0.01
or some other number.
或一些其它数字。
And if it is 0.01, another way
如果是0.01，另一种方式，
to say this to use the
用PCA的语言来表述，
language of PCA is that 99% of the variance is retained.
就是99％的方差性会被保留。
I don't really want to, don't
不必担心
worry about what this phrase
这个短语
really means technically but this
的真正含义，这个
phrase "99% of variance is retained" just means
短语“99％的方差会被保留”只是说
that this quantity on the left is less than 0.01.
左侧的这个量小于0.01
And so, if you
所以，如果你
are using PCA and if you want
使用主成分分析，如果你想
to tell someone, you know,
告诉别人，
how many principle components you've
你保留了多少主成分
retained it would be
这样去表述会
more common to say well, I
比较好，我
chose k so that 99% of the variance was retained.
选择k使得99％的方差被保留。
And that's kind of a useful thing
这是一个需要知道的有用的
to know, it means that you
东西，这意味着你
know, the average squared projection
知道，平均投影误差平方
error divided by the total
除以数据总方差，
variation that was at most 1%.
结果不会超过1%。
That's kind of an insightful
这样的表述方式是很有见地
thing to think about, whereas if
的，否则
you tell someone that, "Well I
你告诉别人，“嗯，我
had to 100 principle
有100主成分
components" or "k was equal
或”在1000维的数据中
to 100 in a thousand dimensional
k等于100“
data" it's a little
这对于
hard for people to interpret
人们来说
that.
不太好理解
So this number 0.01 is what people often use.
因此这个数字0.01是人们经常使用的东西。
Other common values is 0.05,
其他常见的值是0.05，
and so this would be 5%,
因此，这将是5％，
and if you do that then
如果你这样做，那么
you go and say well 95%
你会说95％的
of the variance is
方差
retained and, you know
会保留，你知道
other numbers maybe 90% of the variance is
其它数字也许90％的方差被
retained, maybe as low as 85%.
保留，也许低至85％。
So 90% would correspond to say
因此，90％将对应于说
0.10, kinda 10%.
0.10，或10％。
And so range of values
所以，值的范围从
from, you know, 90, 95,
90，95，
99, maybe as low as 85% of
99，也许低至85％
the variables contained would be a fairly typical range in values.
都是一些具有代表性的范围。
Maybe 95 to 99
也许95到99
is really the most
是真正最
common range of values that people use.
对被使用的范围
For many data sets you'd be
对于许多数据集你会
surprised, in order to retain
惊讶，为了保留
99% of the variance, you can
99％的方差，你可以
often reduce the dimension of
往往减少数据维数
the data significantly and still retain most of the variance.
但仍保留大部分的方差。
Because for most real life
因为对于真实世界的数据
data says many features are
来说，许多特征都
just highly correlated, and so
是高度相关的，因此
it turns out to be possible
结果证明：
to compress the data a
对数据进行
lot and still retain you
很多压缩，仍然可以保留
know 99% of the variance
99％的方差
or 95% of the variance. So how do you implement this?
或95％的方差。那么，你如何实现呢？
Well, here's one algorithm that you might use.
那么，这里提供一个你可能会用到的算法。
You may start off, if you
你可以开始了，如果你
want to choose the value of
要选择K的值，
k, we might start off with k equals 1.
我们开始可以给K赋值1
And then we run through PCA.
然后我们运行PCA算法
You know, so we compute, you
然后我们计算，你
reduce, compute z1, z2, up to zm.
减少，计算Z1，Z2，一直到ZM。
Compute all of those x1 approx
计算所有这些X1-approx
approx and so on up to xm approx
到 XM-approx
and then we check if 99% of the variance is retained.
然后我们检查，是否保留了99％的方差。
Then we're good and we use k equals 1.
如果保留了，那么我们让K等于1。
But if it isn't then what we'll do we'll next try K equals 2.
但如果不是，那么我们将做什么，我们接下来会尝试让K等于2。
And then we'll again
然后我们将再次
run through this entire procedure and
运行PCA算法，
check, you know is this expression satisfied.
检查一下，是否满足表达式。
Is this less than 0.01. And if not then we do this again.
是否小于0.01。如果没有的话，我们重复这个步骤。
Let's try k equals 3,
让我们试着让k等于3，
then try k equals 4,
然后尝试k等于4，
and so on until maybe
依此类推，直至也许
we get up to k equals
我们让k等于
17 and we find 99% of
17，我们发现99％的
the data have is retained and then
的数据已被保留，然后
we use k equals 17, right?
我们使得k等于17，对吗？
That is one way
这是一种方式
to choose the smallest value
来选择最小的K
of k, so that and 99% of the variance is retained.
从而使99％的方差被保留。
But as you can imagine,
但正如你可以想像的，
this procedure seems horribly inefficient
这个过程看上去非常低效
we're trying k equals one, k equals two, we're doing all these calculations.
我们尝试让k等于1，k等于2，我们正在做的所有这些计算。
Fortunately when you implement
幸运的是，当你实现
PCA it actually, in
PCA是，在
this step, it actually gives us
这一步， 它实际上给了我们
a quantity that makes it
一个量，使得它
much easier to compute these things as well.
我们可以更容易地计算这些东西。
Specifically when you're calling
特别是当你调用
SVD to get these
SVD得到这些
matrices u, s, and d,
矩阵U，S和D，
when you're calling usvd on the
当你在协方差矩阵Σ上
covariance matrix sigma, it also
调用usvd，它也会
gives us back this matrix
给我们返回矩阵
S and what
S
S is, is going to
S实际上将会是
be a square matrix an N by N matrix in fact,
一个N*N的方阵。
that is
就是说
diagonal.
对角线。
So is diagonal entries s one
因此对角线元素s1
one, s two two, s
1，S2，S3
three three down to s
直到
n n are going to
Sn都将
be the only non-zero elements of
是这个矩阵的唯一的非零元素
this matrix, and everything off
并且对角线之外
the diagonals is going to be zero.
的所有元素都将是0。
Okay?
OK？
So those big O's that I'm drawing,
So 我正在画的这些大O，
by that what I mean is
我想表达的意思是
that everything off the diagonal
在这个矩阵中
of this matrix all of those
对角线之外的所有
entries there are going to be zeros.
元素都是0
And so, what is possible
所以，在这里向表示的
to show, and I won't prove
但我在这里不给出证明
this here, and it turns out
但事实证明
that for a given value of
对于一个给定的K
k, this quantity
这个量
over here can be computed much more simply.
的计算将会比较简单
And that quantity can be computed
而且这个量可以这样计算：
as one minus sum from
1减去
i equals 1 through
从1到k
K of Sii divided by
的sii的和
sum from I equals 1
除以从1到n的
through N of Sii.
的Sii的和。
So just to say that it words, or
所以只是
just to take another
从另一个角度
view of how to explain that,
来进行解释的话
if K equals 3 let's say.
如果K等于3，比如
What we're going to do to
我们将要做的是
compute the numerator is sum
计算分子的和
from one--  I equals 1
从i=1到
through 3 of of Sii, so just
3 的sii的值，所以仅仅
compute the sum of these first three elements.
计算前三个元素的和。
So that's the numerator.
这就是分子。
And then for the denominator, well that's
然后对于分母，
the sum of all of these diagonal entries.
计算对角项的和。
And one minus the ratio of
然后1减去这个比值
that, that gives me this
那给了我这个量
quantity over here, that I've
在这里，我用
circled in blue.
蓝色圆圈标注的。
And so, what we can do
所以，我们需要做的，
is just test if this
只是测试，这个值
is less than or equal to 0.01.
是否小于或等于0.01。
Or equivalently, we can test
或者等价地，我们可以测试
if the sum from
1到k的
i equals 1 through k, s-i-i
sii的和，
divided by sum from i
除以
equals 1 through n, s-i-i
1到n的sii的和，
if this is greater than or
如果是大于或
equal to 0.99, if you
等于0.99，如果你
want to be sure that 99% of the variance is retained.
要确保99％的方差被保留。
And so what you can do
那么你可以这样做：
is just slowly increase k,
只是慢慢地增加K，
set k equals one, set k equals
让k=1，让k=2
two, set k equals three and so
k=3，以此类推
on, and just test this quantity
然后检查哪个是
to see what is the
使得99％的方差被保留的
smallest value of k that ensures that 99% of the variance is retained.
的最小值。
And if you do
如果你这样做
this, then you need to call
那么你需要调用
the SVD function only once.
一次SVD。
Because that gives you the
因为这可以给你
S matrix and once you
矩阵S，一旦你
have the S matrix, you can
获得矩阵S，你可以
then just keep on doing
继续进行这种
this calculation by increasing
计算通过增加
the value of K in the
分子中
numerator and so you
K的值，而且你
don't need keep to calling SVD over
不需要反复调用SVD
and over again to test out the different values of K.
来测试出K的不同值
So this procedure is much more
所以此过程是更
efficient, and this can
高效的，这可以
allow you to select the
允许你选择
value of K without needing
k的值而不用
to run PCA from scratch
从头到尾
over and over. You just run SVD once, this
重复运行PCA。只需计算一次奇异值分解，这
gives you all of these diagonal numbers,
给你所有这些对角线的数字，
all of these numbers S11, S22 down to SNN,
所有这些数字充S11，S22一直到Snn的，
and then you can
然后你就可以
just you know, vary K
你知道的，变化K
in this expression to find
在这个表达式中来查找
the smallest value of K, so
k的最小值，使得
that 99% of the variance is retained.
99％的方差被保留。
So to summarize, the way
总结一下，
that I often use, the
我经常使用的方法，
way that I often choose K
我一般选择K的方法，
when I am using PCA for compression
当我使用PCA进行压缩时，
is I would call SVD once
我会在协方差矩阵上进行一次
in the covariance matrix, and then
SVD，然后
I would use this formula and
我会用这个公式，
pick the smallest value of
挑选k的最小值
K for which this expression is satisfied.
使得k满足这个公式。
And by the way, even if you
顺便说一句，即使你
were to pick some different value
是挑选一些不同的k
of K, even if you were
值，即使你
to pick the value of K
手动选择K值，
manually, you know maybe you
你知道，也许你
have a thousand dimensional data
有一千个维度数据
and I just want to choose K equals one hundred.
我只是想选择K=100。
Then, if you want to explain
然后，如果你想解释
to others what you just did,
给别人你刚才做了什么，
a good way to explain the performance
一个向他们
of your implementation of PCA to
解释你的PCA算法性能的好方法是
them, is actually to take
其实是取
this quantity and compute what
这个量，并计算结果
this is, and that will
这将
tell you what was the percentage of variance retained.
告诉你方差被保留的百分比。
And if you report that number, then,
如果你报告这个数字，那么，
you know, people that are familiar
你知道，熟悉PCA的人
with PCA, and people can
他们可以
use this to get a
通过这个来
good understanding of how well
很好的理解
your hundred dimensional representation is
你的100维表示是如何
approximating your original data
逼近原始数据的
set, because there's 99% of variance retained.
因为有99％的方差保留。
That's really a measure of your
这真的是对你的构造误差的
square of construction error, that
好的度量，那个比值
ratio being 0.01, just
为0.01，正好
gives people a good intuitive
给人一种很好的直观的
sense of whether your implementation
感受，是否你的PCA
of PCA is finding a
找到了一个
good approximation of your original data set.
对原始数据集的良好近似。
So hopefully, that gives you
所以希望，那给你
an efficient procedure for choosing
一个高效的步骤去选择
the number K. For choosing
K，将你的数据维数
what dimension to reduce your
进行缩减，
data to, and if
并且如果
you apply PCA to very
你将PCA应用到
high dimensional data sets, you know, to like
高维数据集，你知道，比方说
a thousand dimensional data, very often,
1000维数据，很常见的维数，
just because data sets tend
只是因为数据集往往
to have highly correlated
有高度相关
features, this is just a
的特征，这仅仅是一个
property of most of the data sets you see,
你看到的大部分数据集的一个属性，
you often find that PCA
你经常会发现PCA
will be able to retain ninety nine
将可保留99
per cent of the variance or say,
的方差或者说，
ninety five ninety nine, some
95，99，一些
high fraction of the variance,
高比例的方差，
even while compressing the data
即使是因为一个很大的因素
by a very large factor.
对数据进行压缩